9号秘事
第七季   第二集
9班
金老师
规划表 2021年-2022年
2021年 9班 - 哈迪老师
希望
早上好 九班同学们
Bore da, dosbarth naw.
早上好 爱德华兹校长
Bore da, Mr Edwards.
这是你们的新老师 柯蒂斯老师
Dyma'ch athro newydd Mr Curtis
他会教你们英语
ac mae'n mynd I'ch dysgu chi yn Saesneg.
我跟他们说
I was telling them
你所有的课都会用英语上
you're going to be taking all your lessons in English,
英语对于将来想离开村子
which is a very important skill
外出探险的人来说
for those adventurers amongst you
是个非常重要的技能
who might be thinking about leaving the village in the future.
柯蒂斯老师曾在伦敦的一所学校教书
Mr Curtis used to teach at a school in London
所以我相信他有许多激动人心的故事
so I'm sure he'll have all sorts of exciting stories
会讲给我们听的
to tell us.
伦敦人会花两英镑买杯咖啡 是吗
They pay £2 for a coffee, don't they?
还有别的
And the rest.
我的天啊 好家伙
Oh, dearie me, imagine that!
大家都知道
Now, as you all know,
你们的金老师在经过美好的一年后
your previous teacher, Mr King, had to leave us
不得不离开我们了
after a wonderful year.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
不过他在旅途中
But he has sent us this postcard from his travels,
给我们寄来了这张明信片
and I wondered if one of you
你们谁来给全班同学念一下
would like to read it to the class.
-我 -我
-Me! -Me.
凯莉 你要不要来念一下
Ceri, would you care to do the honours?
好孩子
Good girl.
亲爱的九班 我在澳洲问候大家
"Dear Class 9, greetings from down under.
我在这里过得很好
"I'm having an amazing time
我想新学期也该开始了吧
"and I'm thinking of you, as you start your next chapter.
我非常怀念和你们在一起的时光
"I cherish the memory of our time together
能够真正地了解你们每个人
"and getting to know all of you so closely.
爱你们的金老师
"Much love, Mr King."
多好的人
What a man!
多好的老师 太好了
What a teacher, what a man.
那么 该上课了
Anyway, back down to reality.
柯蒂斯老师 交给你了
Mr Curtis, over to you.
谢谢你 校长
Thank you, Headmaster.
那么 我有个问题
So, here's a question
我和皮诺曹有什么不同呢
what's the difference between me and Pinocchio?
我很开心能来威尔士
I'm glad to be in Wales.
啊 因为皮诺曹被鲸鱼吃掉了
Ah, now that is because Pinocchio was eaten by a whale.
我说得对吗 柯蒂斯老师
Have I got that right, Mr Curtis?
对 我只是开了个玩笑
Yes, it was just a joke.
这就是个玩笑 九班的同学们
It was a joke, Class 9.
是个玩笑
A joke.
继续上课
Carry on.
大家都知道
So, as you all know,
期末演出的主题都是跟环境有关的
our end-of-term assembly is going to be all about the environment.
那么 环境是什么意思呢
So, what does that mean?
谁来说一下
Anyone.
-尤恩 -呃
-Euan? -Erm...
是我们教室
Our classroom?
对 教室是我们最熟悉的环境 还有呢
Yes, that's our immediate surroundings, what else?
还有田野
Ooh, fields!
对 很好 环境包括了 人类或动植物
Yes, good. It's any place where people and plants
生活和生长的所有地方
and animals actually live and grow.
那么哪些事情会影响我们的环境呢
So what types of things will affect our environment?
哦 人豆 老师
Oh, human beans, sir.
你说什么 格温
What's that, Gwen?
人豆
Human beans.
不是人豆 我们不是蔬菜
Not human beans, we're not vegetables,
是人类 对
but human beings, yes,
我们人类确实对环境有影响
we certainly have an impact.
我们对环境的影响有正面的
And we can affect our environment
也有负面的
in positive ways and in negative ways.
那么 哪些正面的事情是可以做的呢
So, what are some of the positive things that we can do?
凯莉
Ceri?
回收利用
Recycling.
非常好 凯莉 回收利用
Very good, Ceri. Yes. Recycling.
还有别的吗
Anyone else?
你们听说过格蕾塔·桑伯格这个人吗
Well, who here has heard of Greta Thunberg?
都没听说过吗
None of you?
好吧
OK. Er...
你们应该都听说过全球变暖吧
You've probably all heard of global warming?
没听说过 那么气候变化呢
No? How about climate change?
好吧 你们去年应该看过一些这方面的报道
OK, well, you should have covered some of this last year,
我来问问大家
but let me ask you this...
你们说飓风是什么原因造成的
What do you think causes hurricanes?
上帝放的屁
God farting!
不对 别胡说 欧文
No, don't be silly, Owen.
这是个很严肃的话题
This is actually a really serious subject.
作为你们的家庭作业 我希望你们放学后
So, for your homework, I want you all to go home
学习一下有关全球变暖和臭氧层的知识
and learn all about global warming and the ozone layer.
老师 金老师说我们不用做家庭作业的
Sir, Mr King said we didn't have to do homework.
很遗憾
Well, I'm really sorry,
不过金老师不再是你的老师了 我才是
but Mr King isn't your teacher now, I am.
你们或许还没有意识到
You know, I don't know if you realise it,
这会是影响你们和你们未来的
but this is the number one topic
最重要的话题之一
that's going to affect you and all your futures,
所以你们对此一无所知是不行的
so it really isn't something that you can afford to be ignorant about!
抱歉
Sorry.
好了 大家回去写一篇小作文
Now, I want you all to do a paragraph
下周一交上来
and bring it in on Monday.
好了 现在把课本拿出来
Right, you can all get your books out
默读20分钟 开始
and do silent reading for 20 minutes. Off you go.
校长
Oh, Headmaster?
我能跟您说句话吗
Er, could I have a word?
可以啊 艾伦 有什么事吗
Of course, Alan. How can I help?
您有金老师的电子邮箱吗
I wondered if you had an email address for Mr King.
电子邮箱
Email...
是那个带蓝色小鸟的图标吗
Is that the one with the little blue bird?
不对 那个应该是推特
No, I think that's Twitter.
对 你说得对
That's right, yes, tash-tag.
电子邮箱应该是带@的那个吧
Email is the @ sign,
我记得我办公室里
isn't it? Yes, I think I've got
有张纸上写的就是这个
a piece of paper with that on in my office.
哦 谢谢 我想和他聊聊他
Oh, thanks, it's just I'd love to talk to him
去年教的内容和用的是什么教程
about what he covered last year and what curriculum he's been using.
嗯 没问题
Well, no problem.
我让梅根找出来 回头再给你
I'll ask Megan to dig it out and I'll get back to you.
谢谢
Thanks.
其他的都进展顺利吗
All good otherwise?
对 是的
Er, yeah, I think so.
你期末演出的节目开始排练了吗
Have you started rehearsing for your assembly yet?
金老师的节目一向是很华丽的
Mr King's were always very lavish.
就像是伦敦西区的戏剧作品一样
Like West End theatre productions!
我会 我会弄得超好看的
Well, I'll... I'll try and make mine Wicked.
是部音乐剧
That's a musical. Ah.
你又说笑话了
Another one of your jokes.
那我就等着看了
Well, I look forward to it.
看到孩子们站在舞台上 是件赏心悦目的事情
Always a joy to see the children take centre stage.
艾伦 你也知道这是一所很小的学校
We're a small school, Alan, as you can see,
我们已经有好几次差点关门了
and we've very nearly been closed down a few times,
不过能把你这样的
but bringing in teachers such as yourself,
经历丰富的老师招进来
with all your experience of the world,
确实有助于孩子们成长 你明白吗
it really helps the children grow, you know?
嗯 我也是这么希望的 校长 真的
Well, that's... That's all I want, Headmaster, it really is.
那就好 行吧 我回头把电子邮箱找出来
Jolly good. Right, well, I'll get that bmail for you,
让梅根发短信给你
and I'll get Megan to send it to you as a text.
做出英国教育的标准吧
Take that, Ofsted!
-非常好 你画的是个南瓜吗 很好 -对
-That's very good. Is that going to be a pumpkin? Great. -Yes.
上面还有吓人的眼睛
With some scary eyes on it.
挂起来的时候
Make sure that your paint isn't dripping
可别让油彩滴下来
when you hang up your paintings, OK?
-欧文 你的画还没干吗 -呃 是啊老师
-Is yours still wet, Owen? -Er, yes, sir.
那先把它放在托盘上
Well, put it on top of the tray for now.
画得非常好 等画干了以后
That's fantastic. And then, when it is dry,
我们再把这些都挂起来展览
we will stick them all up on the display.
哦 谢谢你 凯莉 太好了
Oh, thank you, Ceri, that's great.
好了 休息15分钟 脱了围裙 去玩一会儿吧
OK, you've got 15 minutes. Aprons off, go and have a play.
走吧 去玩吧 去吧
Walking. That's it, off you go.
凯莉 我有话要问你
Ceri, could I have a word with you, please?
我说 你想什么呢
I mean, what were you thinking? Hmm?
这些蝌蚪现在变不成青蛙了 对吧
Those tadpoles are not going to turn into frogs now, are they?
为什么不行
Why not?
你把它们放在壶里煮了呀
Because you boiled them in the kettle.
你为什么这么干 凯莉
I mean, why would you do that, Ceri?
因为全球变暖了
Global warming.
我是让你去研究 没让你实践
I asked you to research it, not recreate it.
金老师还吃过金鱼呢
Mr King once ate a goldfish.
是吗 我不管金老师干过什么
Yeah, well, I don't care what Mr King did.
我有些担心你了 凯莉
I'm getting a bit concerned about you, Ceri.
上个礼拜你把西蒙的脸
I mean, last week,
按进他的生日蛋糕里了 对吧
you pushed Simon's face into his birthday cake, didn't you?
他的头发要是被蜡烛点着了怎么办
What if his hair had caught fire on the candles?
你看过迈克尔·杰克逊的视频吗
Have you seen that Michael Jackson video?
不是舔人屁股的那个
Not the one about licking boys' bottoms,
是他的头发着火的那个视频
the one where his hair caught fire.
他险些就毁容了
It very nearly disfigured him...
甚至更严重
..even more.
迈克尔·杰克逊是谁
Who's Michael Jackson?
算了
Never mind.
你家里怎么样 有什么想跟我说的吗
Is there anything going on at home that you want to tell me about?
-我家的房子在扩建呢 -哦
-We're having an extension. -OK.
你爸爸妈妈相处融洽吗 没有吵架吧
Are Mummy and Daddy getting on all right? No shouting?
有让你烦心的事吗
Something upsetting you?
我不想看到世界末日
I don't want the world to end.
那肯定不会
Well, it's not going to end.
-谁跟你说会世界末日的 -反抗灭绝组织
-Who said it's going to end? -The stinking rebellion.
什么组织
Who?
是你让我们看的 还是家庭作业
You asked us to read about it for homework.
你是说气候变化的抗议者吗
You mean the climate change protesters?
吓到我了
It frightened me.
千万别害怕 凯莉
Oh, you mustn't be frightened, Ceri.
我的意思是 你应该感受那种情绪
I mean, you should feel
然后用它做一些有意义的事情
that emotion and then do something positive with it.
没关系的
It's all right.
好了 好了 对不起 吓到你了
There, there. Sorry it frightened you.
想去外面玩一会儿吗
Now, do you want to go and play outside or...
还是和我说说话
..or do you want to stay inside with me?
我们说说话吧
Stay with you.
好孩子
Good girl.
你是饿了吗
Little bit peckish, are we?
哦 抱歉 校长
Oh, sorry, Headmaster,
我就是
I was just, erm,
在练给孩子们表演的小魔术
just practising a trick for the children.
这倒是教食物链知识的一个办法
Well, that's one way of teaching the food chain.
艾伦 方便的话 我有几句话想单独和你谈谈
I... I just wanted to have a quiet word with you, Alan,
-行吗 -当然可以
-if you don't mind. -Yes, of course.
你来面试的时候
When you came in for your interview,
你说你很想来我们这种
you said you were keen to move to a smaller school,
规模比较小的学校任教
like ours, away from the cut and thrust,
远离俗世的纷纷扰扰
shall we say, of inner-city education
享受更宁静的生活方式
and embrace a quieter pace of life.
对 这也是医生给我的建议
Yes, it's, erm, literally what the doctor ordered.
我知道在涉及心理健康的问题上
Now, I know it's important we talk sensitively
应该谨慎
about mental health,
不过我还是想跟你明确一下
so I just wanted to clarify...
你有些精神上的问题 是吗
You went a bit doolally, didn't you?
是 是
No. No, I...
是因为工作量大了些
It was just the workload.
我有些疲惫 身心俱疲
I was exhausted, both physically, mentally.
我有一段时间确实迷失了自我
I did lose myself for a time,
不过 来到这里对我非常有好处
but, erm, coming here's done me the world of good.
您为什么这么问
Why do you ask?
是这样
Well, the thing is...
有人举报了你
..an allegation has been made against you,
我就有责任展开调查了
and it's my duty to investigate it.
-什么举报 -我暂时不能说
-What allegation?  -I can't divulge that at the moment.
-那 是谁举报的我 -她也不想暴露身份
-Well, who's made it? -She doesn't want to say.
-是个女学生吗 -也许是也许不是
-So it's a girl?  -She may or may not be.
关键是我向凯莉的父母保证过
The point is I promised Ceri's parents
举报者的身份要绝对保密
that she, or he, would have absolute anonymity.
-所以是凯莉 对吗 -是的
-So it's Ceri?  -Yes.
好吧
Right.
既然你已经了解到了一部分情况
So now you've wormed that out of me, can you tell me
你有什么要说的吗
in your own words
周二上午课间休息时发生了什么
what happened Tuesday morning, break time?
-什么叫发生了什么 -什么也没发生啊
-What do you mean, what happened? -Nothing happened.
她的行为有些古怪
She'd been behaving strangely for a while.
她把蝌蚪都弄死了
She killed all the tadpoles.
我把她留下想跟她谈谈而已
I kept her behind to talk to her about it.
你没有让她做什么
And at no point did you ask her
犯忌讳的事情吗
if she wanted to play the hairy meat whistle?
什么 没有
What? No.
你没说过
And you didn't say,
你想看看老师的蝌蚪吗 这种话
"Do you want to see how sir can make his own tadpoles?"
-当然没有 这太可怕了 -你确定吗
-Definitely not, that's horrible. -Are you sure?
确定 说没说过我记得很清楚
Yes, I think I'd remember saying that.
那你觉得这种话她是从哪儿听来的
Well, where do you suppose she's got this from, then?
我相信儿童读物里肯定没有
Because I don't recall that being in the Biff and Chip books.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许她在网上看了一些不好的内容
Maybe she saw something inappropriate online,
这也是常有的事
it happens all the time.
可我们这里没有无线网络
Not with our Wi-Fi connection, it doesn't.
我下载《乡村档案》都用了一个周末
It takes me all weekend to download one Countryfile.
你和她提过迈克尔·杰克逊对男的
Did you talk to her about Michael Jackson doing things
菊花所做之事吗
with boys' anuses?
提到过 可没提其他的事
Yes, but I never said anuses.
这就够了
Well, that's something.
我已经说服了凯莉的父母
Now, I've talked the girl's parents down
不要提出正式起诉
from making an official complaint,
如果可以的话
but I don't want to drag the police into it
我也不想把警察牵扯进来
if I can help it.
我们是一所独立学校
We're an independent school and we like to deal
我们喜欢在内部处理这类事情
with these types of things within the community.
什么 以前发生过这种事吗
What, so this has happened before?
你初来乍到 我不会开玩笑的
You're new here, and I'm not being funny,
可我不能仅凭你说的就相信你 艾伦
but I don't know you from Alan.
-是亚当 -哦 抱歉 我以为是艾伦呢
-It's Adam. -Oh, sorry, I thought it was Alan.
亚当 我相信你能理解 作为这所学校的校长
I'm sure you understand, Adam, that, as head of this school,
我必须首先确定事实真相
I have to establish the facts of this matter
然后才能把凯莉交回到你手上
before I can allow Ceri back into your clutches, so to speak.
对 没错 您需要我写一份声明吗
Yes, of course. You want me to make a statement?
不用 不过我需要你给我看你的鸡巴
No, I want you to show me your penis.
什么
What?
凯莉描述得非常细致
The girl has given quite a vivid description
她还用橡皮泥捏了个模型
and I believe made a Plasticine model,
可是我不想碰
but I didn't want to touch it.
我要看看她捏的和你的是不是一样
I need to see if this tallies with the real thing.
所以还得弄个辨认队列吗 如果不是我的
So I've got to do an identity parade? What if it's not mine?
你还要像寻找灰姑娘那样四处去寻找吗
Are you going to take it around the kingdom like Cinderella?
别耍小聪明 亚当
Don't be facetious, Adam,
我是在想办法了解事实真相
I'm trying to get to the bottom of this, one way or the other.
要么是你说谎 要么是凯莉在说谎
Either you're lying or the girl's lying.
这怎么可能
I just can't believe this.
我可以随时联系你的工会代表
I can always contact your union representative...
不
No...
No.
算了 快点看 行了吧
Well, just make it quick, all right?
这多干净利落 这样你我都省事
All very neat and tidy, that's what I like to see.
你究竟在找什么
What are you looking for, exactly?
啊 这下就明白了
Ah, now that would be telling.
俗话说
They say...
世上没有一模一样的两片雪花
..they're like snowflakes no two are alike.
太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
抱歉 温妮 我们这儿正忙着呢
Oh, sorry, Winnie, we're a bit busy here.
你好 柯蒂斯老师 你还没走啊
Hello, Mr Curtis, you're here late.
我现在可以打扫了吗
Is it all right for me to clean now?
现在不方便
Not just at the moment.
哦 别担心温妮 她什么都看不见
Oh, don't worry about Winnie, she's blind as a bat.
没事的 温妮 你忙你的
It's fine, Winnie, you go right ahead.
是你吗 爱德华兹校长
Is that you, Mr Edwards?
原来你也在啊 你还在忙吗
I didn't see you down there. You keeping busy?
是啊 我一向都很忙的
Yes, I've got my hands full, as usual.
没关系 我能把你身边打扫干净的
Don't worry, I can clean around you.
我得省出时间来清理男生的厕所
I have to save some time to tackle the boys' toilets.
他们拉的粑粑实在是
The size of some of those stools...
真不知道他们在家里都吃了什么
I don't know what their mothers feed them.
实在是太难清理了
Like airport Toblerones, some of them.
可以了吗
Are you all done here?
可以了 是的
I think so, yes.
等我调查清楚这件事 我会再来找你的
I'll be in touch once I've got my head around this.
谢谢你 亚当
Thank you, Adam.
我们就是 讨论一下新的绘画创作
We were just, erm, discussing a possible arts project.
哦 我还以为他在给你的鸡巴拍照呢
Oh, I thought he was taking photographs of your cock.
好了 九班 我发的是关于分数的卷子
OK, Class 9, I'm handing out these worksheets on fractions.
给你们15分钟
You have got 15 minutes.
能做多少做多少
Do as many as you can.
记得把名字写在最上面
Remember to put your names at the top, please.
老师 凯莉怎么了
Sir, what happened to Ceri?
你想问什么
What do you mean?
-她去哪儿了 -我不知道
-Where is she?  -I don't know.
别说话了 欧文
Now tight lips, please, Owen.
听我说 现在不是你说话的时候
We listen with these, not these.
安静
Quiet.
没听见吗 安静
I said, quiet!
那是什么
What have you got there?
欧文 什么东西
Owen, what is that?
-没什么 老师 -当我是白痴吗 拿出来
-Nothing, sir!  -I'm not an idiot, show me.
在谁手里
All right, who's got it?
拿出来 给我交出来 快点儿
Give it to me. Give it to me now.
这是什么 格温
What's this? Gwen?
格温
Gwen?
是胡萝卜 老师
Carrot, sir.
胡萝卜
A carrot?
那你笑什么
Well, why are you laughing, then?
是不是因为这像个鸡巴
Is it because this bit looks like a penis?
又大又软的鸡巴
A big floppy penis?!
怎么了 柯蒂斯老师
Everything all right, Mr Curtis?
啊 我们在教分数 还有生物
Yes, we were just doing fractions and...biology.
两门课一起上 有意思
Interesting combination.
我把凯莉·摩根给你带来了
I have young Ceri Morgan for you.
去坐下吧 凯莉
Ceri, would you like to take a seat? Good girl.
这下没事了吧 校长
Everything, er, all right now, Headmaster?
没事了没事了 都解决了 没什么麻烦了
Yes, yes, all cleared up, no further action required.
可以说这两张照片
Suffice to say there was quite a big discrepancy
之间的差别很大
between the two images.
为了你好 我必须要确保万无一失
In your favour, I have to add. So, you know, every cloud...
哦 好吧 谢谢
Oh, well. Good, thanks.
继续上课吧
As you were.
你能回来就好 凯莉
It's nice to have you back, Ceri.
我说一句
Just to say,
如果想不出答案
if you're struggling to find the right answer...
也不要胡编乱造
..don't just make something up,
因为说谎是有代价的
because that has consequences.
有问题可以举手提问
Just put your hand up and talk to me.
如果我不知道发生了什么 我就帮不了你们
I can't help you if I don't know what's going on.
所以不要在我背后说三道四
So don't go behind my back.
明白吗 那就好
OK? Good.
哦 你好 温妮
Oh. Hi, Winnie.
哦 你好
Oh, hello, dear.
你要不要些韭菜呢
I just wondered if you wanted to take a leek.
什么
Sorry?
参加丰收节啊
For the harvest festival.
今年我的收成不错
I've had a good crop this year.
土豆又大又漂亮还有小萝卜
Nice big potatoes, radishes...
我的大头菜还得奖了呢
My turnips have won prizes, you know.
哦 那恭喜你了
Well, congratulations.
温妮
Winnie...
金老师和孩子们相处得好吗
What was, erm, Mr King like with the children?
哦 上课的时候我不知道
Oh, well, I'm not in the lessons, like.
不过他们好像都挺喜欢他的
They all seemed to love him.
他就像是个大明星
He was a real star!
这个也很棒
Quite a dish, too.
好得有些难以置信了
He sounds too good to be true.
嗯 你的萝卜还真不错 温妮
Well, your, erm, neeps are very impressive, Winnie.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是一款全新的内衣
This is a brand-new Playtex.
塑胸的效果不错
Lift and separate.
我说的是蔬菜
I, er, meant the vegetables.
哦 那是大自然的魔法
Well, that's Mother Nature working her magic.
温妮 我答应校长
Winnie, I promised the headmaster
今天下班前会把报告交给他
I'd get those reports to him by the end of the day
可我差点儿就忘了
it's completely slipped my mind.
你有没有
You don't, erm...You don't happen to have a...
他办公室的钥匙
key to his office, do you?
求你了
Please?
哦 我有
Oh, go on, then.
你动作快些就行了
As long as you're quick.
谢谢你 我马上就还回来
Thank you. I'll be two minutes.
没有姓金的
No King.
校长吗 是我 艾伦·柯蒂斯
Headmaster, it's Alan Curtis.
是亚当啊 有什么事吗
Oh, hello, Adam, what can I do for you?
我有几件要紧的事要跟你说
I need to talk to you urgently about several things,
首先就是金老师
firstly about Mr King.
这所学校根本没有他在这里工作过的任何记录
This school has no record of him ever having worked here.
你说什么 抱歉 我实在是听不清楚
What's that? Sorry, it's a very bad line.
金老师怎么了
Something about Mr King?
九班去年的班主任是哈迪老师
The class teacher last year was a Mr Hardy,
根本就是另外一个人
a completely different person.
我不知道这个姓金的怎么会在这里
I don't know what this King has been doing here,
还允许他接触孩子们
being given access to children, but...
但我认为这里发生过校园暴力事件
..I think there's been abuse going on,
而且被掩盖了下来 我认为你 爱德华兹校长
it's been covered up, and I think you, Mr Edwards,
也是参与者
are part of it!
我听不见你说什么 亚当 通话质量太差了
I'm losing you, Adam, it's a terrible connection.
我现在在地里呢 一会儿就回来找你 好吧
I'm just in the field - I'll come and see you shortly, OK?
你跑不掉的 你听见了吗
You won't get away with this, do you hear?
哦 九班 你们在干嘛
Oh, Class 9, what's this?
我们想让你看看我们的节目
We want to show you our assembly.
哦 我今天想安排你们默读
Oh, well, I was just going to do quiet reading today,
要不明天再说吧
but, erm, maybe tomorrow we could...
求你了 老师
Oh, please, sir,
我们一直在努力学习你教我们的东西
we've been working really hard on what you taught us.
那好吧 来吧
Er... OK, go ahead.
欢迎来看我们的节目
Welcome to our assembly!
我们把自己粘在首相官邸前
We have glued ourselves to the Prime Minister's house
以示对气候变化的抗议
to protest against climate change.
很好
Ha! Very good.
全球变暖是对地球最大的威胁
Global warming is the biggest threat to our planet, planet Earth.
我们能做些什么来阻止它呢
What can we do to stop it?
嘿 说你呢 你在干嘛
Hey, you! What are you doing?
我吗 没干嘛呀 不就是个塑料杯吗
Me? Nothing. It's only plastic.
塑料快让我窒息了
Plastic is slowly choking me...
它填满了我的海洋 杀死了野生动物
..filling my oceans and killing wildlife.
那我该怎么办
What can I do?
回收啊
Recycling!
接招
Take that.
我们回头再回收他
We'll recycle him later.
哦 这么做可不行 九班的同学们
Oh, I don't think that's appropriate, Class 9.
你们在这把椅子上抹什么了
What have you done to this chair?
强力胶
Superglue.
你也是抗议的一部分 老师
You're part of the protest too, sir.
这一点也不好笑 凯莉 够了 可以停了
That isn't funny, Ceri. All right, stop this now.
拯救地球的行动在上千年前就开始了
Saving the planet started thousands of years ago.
最初 地球女神
In the beginning, the Earth Goddess
是通过万物表达自我的女神
was the one who expressed herself through the many.
她是广阔的虚空 是万物之始
She was the great void, the beginning of all things.
所有的灵魂都是 在她神圣的子宫里诞生的
All souls were born from her sacred womb,
在她的躯体所化的地球上 生活一段时间
lived for a span upon her body, the Earth,
死后再回到她的坟墓子宫里
then returned to her tomb-womb at death.
坟墓子宫
Tomb-womb?
抱歉 我想这不是第二阶段教育的内容
I'm sorry, I don't think that's key stage 2.
可是金老师说
But Mr King said...
听着 我不知道金老师是谁
Look, I don't know who this Mr King was
也不知道他教了你们什么 可这不正常 明白吗
or what he was teaching you, but it's not normal, all right?
我会提交正式投诉
I'm going to make an official complaint.
现在麻烦你们把我从这椅子上放开
Now please get me out of this chair.
在15世纪
In the 15th century,
秘鲁的儿童会被献给神
Peru children were sacrificed to the gods
从而结束自然灾害
to try and end natural disasters.
可是到了现代
But in modern times,
我们这些孩子要有自己的方式
we the children are demanding sacrifices of our own.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
等等 这就是你杀死蝌蚪的原因吗
Wait, wait, is this why you killed the tadpoles?
-想阻止气候变化吗 -别说话了 金老师
-To try and end climate change? -No talking, Mr King.
我们是用耳朵听 不是用嘴
We listen with these, not these.
我不是金老师
I'm not Mr King!
闭嘴 老师
Tight lips, sir.
不 不 不要
No, no, don't...
我们已经了解了可再生能源
We have learned about reusable energy.
我们了解了回收和再生
We have learned about recycling and rebirth.
约翰·巴雷康是第一个回收自我
John Barleycorn was the first man to recycle himself,
来回报地球恩赐的人 请听他的故事
to replenish the Earth's bounty. This is his story.
三个人从西方走来
# There were three men come out of the west
用他们的财富做一件事
# Their fortunes for to try
他们郑重起誓
# And these three men made a solemn vow
约翰·巴雷康该死
# John Barleycorn should die... #
这是怎么回事
What on earth is going on here?!
你们想干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我们在做演出表演 校长
We're doing our assembly, sir.
演出 那是下周的事
Assembly? That's not till next week.
你还好吧 柯蒂斯老师
Are you all right, Mr Curtis?
他们对你做了什么 你的嘴怎么了
What have they done to your mouth?
我们正要讲约翰·巴雷康的故事
We were about to tell the story of John Barleycorn.
啊 我最喜欢的故事 接着讲
Ah, my favourite part. Carry on.
约翰·巴雷康代表了自然界的生命循环
John Barleycorn represents the life cycle of the field.
他每年都会在丰收节开始时加冕
He is crowned once a year at the start of the harvest festival
被尊奉为玉米之王
and revered as the Corn King.
如你所发现的那样
Last year, as you discovered,
去年获得这个荣誉的是哈迪老师
Mr Hardy was given the honour.
今年该轮到你了
This year, the crown is yours.
我们发现你是大自然想要的
We discovered you are as nature intended.
没有隔开 还裹着的那种
Uncut and still sheathed.
是新的玉米之王的理想候选人
A perfect candidate for our new corn king.
谢谢你 凯莉 你做得很好
Thank you, Ceri, you did it beautifully.
在退位之后 玉米之王会回归大地
When his reign is ended, the King is returned to the land
以三种死亡为荣
and honoured with a triple death
淹死 勒死和肢解
drowned, strangled and dismembered,
他那筒体断节被埋在田地里
his broken body buried in the field
以确保丰收
to ensure a fertile harvest.
就像是人豆
Like human beans!
没错 格温 就像是人豆
Exactly, Gwen, like human beans.
你和那些伦敦人或许会拍拍肩膀
You and your fancy friends in London may pat yourselves on the back
说你们终于意识到了环境问题
that you've finally woken up to environmental issues, but...
可我们已经为地球牺牲几百年了
..we've been doing our bit for the planet for centuries now.
来吧 孩子们
Come, children.
国王死了 国王万岁
The King is dead. Long live the King.
国王万岁
Long live the King!
温妮 就等你了
Winnie, we're ready for you now.
我的韭菜会感激你的
You're going to do my leeks the world of good.
有三个人从西方走出来
# There were three men come out of the west
他们要财富做一件事
# Their fortunes for to try
他们郑重起誓
# And these three men made a solemn vow
约翰·巴雷康该死
# John Barleycorn should die
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
他们推着他绕田地游行
# They wheeled him all around the field
他是受难的囚徒
# A prisoner to endure
可怜的巴雷康
# And in the barn poor Barleycorn
被放在谷仓的地上
# They laid him upon the floor
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
# Fa la la la la la la
他们雇了一个人 用酸苹果树的树杈
# They hired men with the crab tree sticks
剥下他的皮
# To cut him skin from bone
磨坊主对他更糟糕
# And the miller, he served him worse than that
他把他放在两块大石头中间研磨
# For he ground him between two stones
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la... #